Hey, what's going on, guys?
Welcome to my Mern stack e commerce course, so I just want to take a couple of minutes and kind of
let you know what this course is about, what's required and so on.
So this is a single project cause it's one large project, probably the largest that I've done in the
course.
And it's going to be an e-commerce platform with a full fledged, you know, shopping cart checkout
system will integrate the PayPal API so we can pay with PayPal or credit or debit card.
We'll have a product review and rating system.
Customers will be able to, you know, view all their orders, will have an admin area where you can
manage your users, your products, your orders and so on.
Now, as far as what you need to know to take this course, I would say at least the basics of react.
You definitely don't have to be a pro as long as you know what a component is, what state is, what
props are, just the very basics.
If you've watched a crash course or two, that should be enough.
And as far as the back end, using note and express, you don't really have to have much experience.
But if you can build a simple rest API, that's fine.
You don't know.
You don't have to know, Jason.
Web tokens or anything like that because we're going to go through all that in this course.
All right.
So again, this is project based.
It's not a video documentation type course.
So if you like to jump in and get your hands dirty and actually build something that you can in the
end customize, you can put on your portfolio, then I think you're going to like this course.
So in the next video, I want to jump in and show you a demo of the exact project that will be building.