All right, so I just want to give you guys an overview of what will be building in this course, so
we're going to build this from absolute scratch.
We're going to deploy it to Heroku.
And I'm going to leave the Redux Dev tools open so you can see the actions that are fired off and you
can see the state def and all that stuff.
And if you don't understand this, don't worry about it.
We're going to get to Redox later.
So on the home page here we have our Navar.
We can search products.
We have a link to our shopping cart.
We have a sign in register page.
And right here we have a carousel where we're showing the top rated products and we can click on one
of these.
It takes us to the product page.
And then down here we have the latest products and we have six total in the database.
Now, if we have more than 10, then we're going to show our pagination links down here.
You can see in our state how we get the products.
We also get the number of pages, which is one and the page, which is one.
So if pages is more than one, it'll show the links down here to go to the next page.
So let's click on one of these and take a look at the product page.
We have an image title description.
We have the the overall rating.
So the the average rating, the quantity which pertains to the count in stock.
So if we look at this in the state here, account in stock for this product is three.
So we get an option of three.
And then down here we have our views.
And if you're logged in, you can see a form here to write a review.
And of course, you can only write one review per product.
So I'm just going to pretend like I just came to the site and I'm going to buy this.
So I'll add this to my cart immediately.
It shows it in my shopping cart if I add something else.
So this this Aleksa here is actually out of stock.
So this is disabled.
We can't add it.
So I'll grab this mouse right here.
Add to cart.
Now, if I change the quantity within the car, you'll see that this will actually update over here
the number of items and the price.
And of course, our cart items are stored in local storage.
So we can leave the page.
We can even close the browser and come back and the products will still be here.
So let's proceed to checkout and this is as far as we can go without logging in.
So I'm going to log in as John, which is just a regular customer account, and it'll take me right
to the shipping page and you can see the steps up here.
So sign in shipping payment and then place order.
So I'm going to just put whatever in here.
And this those shipping address will also get saved to local storage so that if you come back, it'll
be here.
So continue now for the payment method, we're going to implement the PayPal API, you can also use
a debit or credit card.
And the way we're going to build it, it's going to be scalable.
So you can add other payment methods if you want, like if you want to add stripe or something like
that.
In fact, if I click continue, you'll see over here calls card save pay method and we have a payment
method, PayPal.
So you could easily, you know, swap that out for Stripe.
You just have to implement Stripe's API.
So here we have basically a summary of everything.
So all of our items, the payment method, the shipping address, the price, including shipping and
taxes.
So we'll click place order.
And what that did is it put in order in the database, but it's set to not paid.
So there's going to be a flag is paid and that's set to false until we actually pay.
Same thing with delivered.
We can set an admin, can set this to delivered as well.
So to pay we can use PayPal.
You can also use a debit or credit card and we're going to set up a fake sandbox account that we can
use.
So you can see sandbox dot PayPal.
So we're not dealing with actual money right now and it's going to lock me in automatically as my fake
John Doe account and these fake bank accounts.
So I'll click pay now and then.
Once that process is, this will reload and now you'll see paid on with the date.
And if we look at our order over here is paid is now set to true payment result we're storing in the
database.
This is actually information from PayPal, including like the PayPal email that the ID stuff like that.
So now this has been paid.
So if I go up here and I view my profile, I can see that order in my profile.
I can see where when it's been paid, I can see it's not been delivered or set out for delivered.
And I can view the details as well.
And then over here I can update my user data if I want.
OK, so we can also leave reviews and we can only leave one review.
You can see already left one here.
So if I try to put something in here, it's going to tell me that I already reviewed this product.
OK, now I'm going to log out here and log back in as an admin.
And when you're an admin, you get this additional dropdown item and we can see all of our users here,
so we have admin, we have John and Jane Doe, which are customers.
And I could edit their information.
I could set them to admin if I wanted to, and then they would be able to, you know, have this functionality.
We can see all the products.
And I'll show you how to add a product in a second.
But if we go here, we can see orders.
This is the order that John Doe just placed.
If I go to details, as long as I'm an admin, I'll see this mark as delivered.
And if I click that, it's going to update the database and you can see is delivered is now set to true
and then delivered at is set to whatever the date and time is.
So now the user can come in to this order page and see that it's been delivered or set for delivered
and let's see.
So products let's go ahead and create a project product.
So as soon as I click this, it's going to create it and bring me to the edit page with some sample
data so I can then add in here.
I'll just say test product and for the price will say 10 and let's do 10 and stock them for the image.
You can either manually put a link in here to an image or you are all to an image or you can choose
to upload.
So I'll just grab this Chrome logo so that gets uploaded and then we click update and there's our test
product.
And if there's more than 10, it'll also have pagination here as well.
As you can see in the state, it uses that same product list state.
So if we go back to the front page here and go down, you'll see the test product.
And we have that product page here that we can add to the cart we can now purchase.
So we can obviously delete them or edit them.
We can delete them.
OK, so that clears that out and now it's gone and we can also search our filters.
So if I just put like IP, that's going to narrow it down to to the iPhone.
If I clear this out and click search, it just takes us to the home page.
So there's actually quite a bit of functionality here.
I mean, it's no eBay, but we're building this from the ground up.
We're not using, you know, woo commerce or something like that.
It's just create react app and then all custom code from there.
No copying and pasting or anything like that.
We do have some just sample products, some sample data that will load.
We're going to build the database ceder so that we can seed the database with products and users, but
that's about it.
Everything else is hand coded and you're going to learn a lot in this course.
Even if you already know react and you know the mission stack, I think you'll still have fun building
this out.
So let's go ahead and get started.