So in this video, I just want to go over my environment, my text editor, some of the extensions I'll
be using and also some of the resources for this course and stuff will be using in the course.
So this is the repository for the final project.
It's under my GitHub account, Brad Trabelsi and its pro shopman.
So you can come here, you can see all the the files for this project.
And also, if you go to the comments, what I tried to do is do a get comment.
After every video, there were a couple times where I forgot.
So there was like a few videos worth of code in in some of these comments.
But for the most part, they match up with each video.
So, for instance, when we created the order pay producer and action.
So if you wanted to see the exact code that was added, you can come here and you could see what was
added or what was removed.
So that should be helpful to you if if something's, you know, if you're messed up with something and
you need to see the final code.
So I'm using Visual Studio code for my text editor.
Chances are a lot of you are using this.
It's very popular in the Web dev community and I would highly recommend it.
But if you want to use, like, sublime text or Adam or some kind of idy, so anything that you use
that you used to, that's absolutely fine.
You don't have to use voice code.
It's just what I use and what I usually suggest.
And it's of course it's cross platform.
Next you need to have not just installed on your machine if you don't just go to NOGs Dog.
And I would suggest grabbing the latest version.
We're actually going to be using its modules on our back end, which is the import syntax.
So it's the same syntax as the front end with react and after version.
I believe it was 14. Six of No Jass.
You don't have to add the experimental modules flag.
So I would definitely suggest using at least 14 dot six.
But if you grab the current version, that would be the best option.
So the next thing that you should have installed is the Get Virgin control system.
I would suggest making comments throughout the course.
It doesn't have to be after every video, but whenever you feel, you know, you see fit, we will be
needing to use git at the end to deploy to Hiroku so you can download it.
They get Dasch AskMen.com or you can install it with homebrewed on a Mac and there's other ways to install
on Linux and stuff.
So Postman is an API tool or an HTTP client that we're going to use to test out backend endpoints or
back end routes before we actually integrate them into our front end and to react and into our reduc
state flow.
So you can download this at Posman dot com.
And then I also want to just give a shout out to my partner on this course, Bushier.
So he had a huge hand in the project for this course and he's actually going to be covering the Q&amp;A
section on Udemy.
So if you have a question, if you run into some issues and you leave a message in the Q&amp;A, either
Boissiere or myself, we'll get back to you.
And he's more than capable of handling the Q&amp;A actually specializes in e-commerce with React and Redux
and Express.
And he also has a YouTube channel like Coding with Boissiere.
So if you want to give him a subscribe.
All right.
So let's jump into Vrsaljko code.
And I just want to kind of go over the extensions in the settings that I'm using, just in case you
want to follow along to a tee and you don't want to run into any issues where, you know, our environments
don't match up or something's happening with with with my screen that's not happening with yours.
So as far as extensions, nothing nothing spectacular.
I'm using this S7 react redux, graphical react, native snippets.
And basically I just use this to quickly generate react components.
So we have shortcuts for lots of different things, imports, exports.
I don't use it too much for that though.
I basically just use it for the for these here.
So to generate react components, if like if you want a class component, you can do RCC.
What we'll be using for the most part is the react arrow function right here.
R.A.F. see.
So react arrow function component export.
I like to use this syntax for my components.
All right, so if that bracket pair there is something I recommend but definitely isn't needed, it
just kind of organizes things visually because it colorize is your curly braces, your brackets, your
parentheses and just makes everything nice and neat.
And you can see, you know what where the curly braces and you can see these are purple, the nested
ones in here are blue.
So I've used that for years, this auto rename tag.
So this works with HTML and J.S. React.
Basically if you change the beginning tag it's going to change the ending tag as well automatically.
So you'll see that happen on my screen.
And that's why and I would suggest adding this to this code.
Let's see what else.
I'm also using the JavaScript S6 code snippets I don't use.
This too much, it's basically for just console logs, you can just do CLG enter and it will print out
console log.
So it's not something you need, but it's something that I do use.
And then lastly, I have prettier install, which is a code formatter.
Now as far as like excellent and setting up lending, I'm not going to do that.
I just want to keep everything kind of bare bones.
But I do use pretty er to to actually remove semicolons.
I don't use semicolon so I set it to delete them if I accidentally put one in.
You can do the other way around as well.
Also for, for single quotes.
And I'll show you my prettier setup in a second, but I do use that.
So now I'm just going to go to my settings here.
And one thing I do use is the Savon format.
So if we search for save or I said that backwards format on save.
You see, I have this checked, and basically what that means is if I edit something, so let's just
open up some file here.
So if I have this, like over here and it's not formatted nicely when I save, it automatically puts
it back.
Also, I'm not using semicolon.
So if I have a semicolon and I save it just gets rid of it if I have double quotes.
So if I choose, you know, to use double quotes here and save it automatically changes it single.
And where I have that configured is in settings and then if we search for prettier.
So my setup is not not too crazy.
I just have a single quote checked and I have semicolons unchecked and I have single quote checked and
then my tab with I'm using to and if if we take a look at my settings file, if we do command shift
P and settings and open the adjacent file here, this is just all my settings, my font size, which
is obviously beefed up so you guys can see it, the terminal font size, prettier single quote set to
true.
So nothing crazy.
I know some people have these insane VSC code configurations, but I don't do that because I, I do
a lot of videos and courses.
So I like to try to keep things as bare bones as possible.
But still using the rules that I like, like no semicolons and, you know, single quote, stuff like
that.
So that's pretty much it for my setup.
So it's up to you on what you want to use.
I know a lot of people use semicolons.
I just stopped using them maybe three or four months ago, but.
But that's it.
So in the next video, we'll jump right in and get started on our project.